U.S. Emergency Board No. 124 Records 5050
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board No. 124 Records
1958
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board
5050
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Transcript of proceedings and exhibits of the Emergency Board No. 124, 1958. Arbitrability, wages and crew case. American Airlines, Inc. vs. Air Line Pilots Association, International, 1939-1958.
3114595
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 22, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
An Emergency Board was appointed by the President on June 19, 1958 to investigate and report on the dispute which had arisen out of notices of intended change in the collective bargaining agreement between the parties. Members of the Board were James A. Healy, chairman, Maynard E. Persig, and Benjamin C. Roberts.
Hearings were begun on July 9 and continued to August 18th* Early In the hearings it became apparent that the principal reason for the failure of mediation efforts over a period of months was the Inability of the parties to resolve the question of whether or not Issues relating to turbined powered aircraft were a proper part of the negotiations. Other issues Involved were wages, scheduling, working conditions, travel time and crew compliment. Once the issues were clarified the Board recommended that the parties resume collective bargaining.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5006: U.S. Emergency Board No. 174 Records 5007: U.S. Emergency Board No. 175 Transcripts and Exhibits 5012: Saul Wallen Papers 5027: U.S. Emergency Board No. 178 Transcripts 5030: U.S. Emergency Board No. 179 Exhibits and Related Material 5036: U.S. Emergency Boards under the Railway Labor Act Reports 5037: U.S. Emergency Board No. 81 Records 5038: U.S. Emergency Board No. 94 Records 5039: U.S. Emergency Board No. 98 Records 5040: U.S. Emergency Board No. 106 Records 5042: U.S. Emergency Board No. 111 Records 5043: U.S. Emergency Board No. 114 Records 5044: U.S. Emergency Board No. 116 Reports and Exhibits 5045: U.S. Emergency Board No. 118 Records 5046: U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records 5047: U.S. Emergency Board No. 120 Records 5048: U.S. Emergency Board No. 121 Records 5051: U.S. Emergency Board No. 125 Records 5052: U.S. Emergency Board No. 129 Records 5053: U.S. Emergency Board No. 130 Records 5054: U.S. Emergency Board No. 133 Exhibits 5055: U.S. Emergency Board No. 134 Records 5056: U.S. Emergency Board No. 135 Records 5057: U.S. Emergency Board No. 137 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5058: U.S. Emergency Board No. 138 Records 5059: U.S. Emergency Board No. 142 Records 5060: U.S. Emergency Board No. 145 Records 5061: U.S. Emergency Board No. 146 Records 5062: U.S. Emergency Board No. 154 Records 5064: U.S. Emergency Board No. 169 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5075: U.S. Emergency Board under the Taft Hartley Act Records 5579: National Mediation Board Emergency Board 180, Train Crew Consists 5934: Arthur Stark Papers on the President's Emergency Board #219
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; Airlines -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States -- Sources; United States. Emergency Board No. 124
3114595
- Transcripts, Airline Pilots Exhibits (174), American Airline Exhibits (33), Additional Exhibits (Box 1)
  - Transcripts. 19 Volumes. 1, 761 pages. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Descriptions of type of Equipment flown by Air Line (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Descriptions of type of Equipment flown by Air Line (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Data relating to hours of work, hours of flying, and compensation of pilots and co-pilots (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Compilation of Schedule Adjustment SectionsAmerican Airlines Employment Agreements, 1939-1951 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and data charts relating to scheduled flights and the percentage of flights that are completed within the scheduled time (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Interim report and preliminary recommendations by David L. Cole, neutral, in the 1954 dispute between American Airlines and its pilots (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - More correspondence and data relating to scheduled flight times, etcetera (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - More correspondence and data relating to scheduled flight times, etcetera (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - More correspondence and data relating to scheduled flight times, etcetera (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - More correspondence and data relating to scheduled flight times, etcetera (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - More correspondence and data relating to scheduled flight times, etcetera (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - More correspondence and data relating to scheduled flight times, etcetera (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and bulletins relating to American Airlines policy change wherein the flight engineers would have to hold pilot qualifications (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and bulletins relating to American Airlines policy change wherein the flight engineers would have to hold pilot qualifications (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and bulletins relating to American Airlines policy change wherein the flight engineers would have to hold pilot qualifications (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and bulletins relating to American Airlines policy change wherein the flight engineers would have to hold pilot qualifications (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence and bulletins relating to American Airlines policy change wherein the flight engineers would have to hold pilot qualifications (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 122)
    Scope and Contents
    For folders 121-132: Bulletins 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 7, 11; Correspondence March 7-August 5, 1957
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletins and correspondence relating thereto, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence relating to the National Mediation Board (Box 1, Folder 134)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence relating to the National Mediation Board (Box 1, Folder 135)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence relating to the National Mediation Board (Box 1, Folder 136)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence relating to the National Mediation Board (Box 1, Folder 137)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence relating to the National Mediation Board (Box 1, Folder 138)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Air Line Pilots Association Negotiating Committee Bulletin 13 (Box 1, Folder 139)
  - Airline Pilots Exhibits - Correspondence relating to the settlement of as many issues as possible previous to mediation (Box 1, Folder 140)